Guide to the F. B. Morrison papers, 1900-1962.
Morrison, F. B. papers, 1900-1962.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
F. B. Morrison papers, 1900-1962.
21-14-1014
F. B. (Frank Barron) Morrison, 1887-1958.
2.6 cubic ft.
Reports, news clippings, correspondence, notebooks, articles, bulletins, journals, pamphlets, photographs, passports, and commencement programs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of Frank B. Morrison, who was Director of the Cornell Agricultural Experiment Station and the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station in Geneva, New York in 1927, and in 1928 became Professor of Animal Husbandry and Animal Nutrition at the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of animal husbandry and animal nutrition.
Frank B. Morrison was born in Fort Atkinson, Wisconsin on May 17, 1887. He was Director of the Cornell Agricultural Experiment Station and the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station in Geneva, New York in 1927, and in 1928 he became Professor of Animal Husbandry and Animal Nutrition at the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell University. He also chaired the Department of Animal Husbandry from 1928-1945. He wrote FEEDS AND FEEDING and numerous articles in his field and endowed a fellowship at Cornell for graduate students in the field of livestock feeding. He retired from Cornell in 1955 and died on April 7, 1958.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes biographical information on Morrison; reports, news clippings, correspondence, and notebooks on trips to Germany, the Philippines, Argentina, Venezuela, Spain, and India; class records, final exams, and other records of an Animal Husbandry course; speeches and articles by Morrison; notes on and various editions of FEEDS AND FEEDING; articles, bulletins, and journals; pamphlets; photographs; passports; commencement programs; and correspondence, including letters to or from William Arnon Henry, Lida M. Henry, C. R. Van Hise, Charles S. Knight, E. S. Savage, A. E. Vinson, J. S. Popov, F. W. Christensen, Elsie Morrison, M. D. Lack, E. F. Ladd, Gustave Bohstedt, J. M. Fargo, A. E. Wise, and F. B. Wise.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Morrison, F. B.1887-1958.; Bohstedt, Gustave.; Christiansen, F. W.; Fargo, J. M.; Henry, Lida M.; Henry, W. A.(William Arnon), 1850-1932.; Knight, Charles S.; Lack, M. D.; Ladd, E. F.; Morrison, Elsie.; Morrison, F. B.(Frank Barron), 1887-1958.; Popov, J. S.; Savage, E. S.(Elmer Seth), 1884-1943.; Van Hise, Charles Richard, 1857-1918.; Vinson, A. E.; Wise, A. E.; Wise, F. B.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences--Faculty.
Subjects:
Animal culture.; Animal nutrition.; Feeds.; College teachers--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1900-1958 and undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1958-1964 (Mrs. Elsie Morrison) (Box 1)
- Frank B. Morrison, biographical (Box 1)
- William Arnon Henry, biographical (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous (personal) (Box 1)
- German Trip with U.C. Commission, 1928. Report of journey. (Box 2)
- Trip to the Philippines, 1937. Book of news clippings. (Box 2)
- Trips to the Argentine, 1949, 1951, 1954. Correspondence and data. (Box 2)
- Trip to Venezuela, 1955. Correspondence. (Box 2)
- "A Study of the Livestock Industry in Venezuela," by Frank B. Morrison and Jorge De Alba, 1954. Mimeo (2 folders). (Box 2)
- Animal Husbandry Course #115, 1948-1954. Class records, final exams, etc. (Box 2)
- Morrison Fellowship in Livestock Feeding, 1951. Awarded to Hernan Caballero D. Correspondence. (Box 2)
- Speeches and/or articles by Frank B. Morrison
  - "A Plan for the Distribution of References on Nutrition Literature" (mimeo) (Box 3)
  - "The Effect of Low Plan Nutrition on Production of Beef Cattle" (mimeo) (Box 3)
  - "Animal Production in an Efficient Food Economy" (reprint from Chronica Botanica, Summer 1948 ) (Box 3)
  - "How Should Roughage be Used?" (carbon typescript) (Box 3)
  - "Feed and Care of the Brood Sow and Litter" (mimeo) (Box 3)
  - "Reducing Feed Costs" (carbon typescript) (Box 3)
  - "Factors Which Have Made Wisconsin a Great Dairy State" (carbon typescript) (Box 3)
  - "Do Swing Fed Good Rations Need a Mineral Supplement" (mimeo) (Box 3)
  - "Substitutes for Corn" (mimeo) (Box 3)
  - "Feeding for Profit" (carbon typescript) (Box 3)
  - Address by Prof. Morrison, 1926, to The American Feed Manufacturers' Association (carbon typescript) (Box 3)
  - "Pasture Crops for Swine" (typescript) (Box 3)
  - "Packers and Stockyards Act - Purpose and Method of Administration" (mimeo) (Box 3)
  - "Figuring Out Economical Rations" (typescript) (Box 3)
  - "Yellow Corn Excels White" (carbon typescript) (Box 3)
  - Home Grown Rations for Milke Production (carbon typescript) (Box 3)
  - "Feeding Farm Animals" (carbon typescript) (Box 3)
  - "Feeding Stuffs" (carbon typescript) (Box 3)
- Notes on Feeds and Feeding (Box 3)
- Data Sheets (Box 3)
- Feeding Reports, Demonstrations, etc. (Box 3)
- Articles NOT by FBM
  - "Protein Supplements with Different Roughages for Fattening Cattle," by C.C. Culbertson, J.M. Evvard, W.E. Hammond, and Q.M. Wallace, Iowa, 1924 (mimeo) (Box 3)
  - "How Much Protein Do Beef Calves Need?" by C.F. Winchester (reprint from Feed Age, n.d. (Box 3)
  - "The Effect of added soluble carbonhydrate upon the digestibility of Protein and Fiber in rations for Swine," by Christos Nicholas Skipitaris, C.U., 1965 (mimeo) (Box 3)
  - "Recommended Nutrient Allowances for Horses," by P.B. Pearson, C.F. Winchester, and A.L. Harvey (mimeo) (Box 3)
  - Summaries of speeches at Centennial Conference, King Ranch 1853-1953, and program (mimeo and printed) (Box 3)
  - "Effects of Dietary Calcium and phosphorus ... in the rat," by S.L. Hansard and M.P. Plumlee (reprint Journal of Nutrition, 1954 ) (Box 3)
  - Also: news clipping articles by various people (Box 3)
- News clippings relating to Frank B. Morrison (Box 3)
- Press Releases. (Box 3)
- Misc. pamphlets (Box 3)
- Photographs
  - FBM (Box 3)
  - W.A. Henry (Box 3)
  - Family photographs (Box 3)
  - Misc. (Box 3)
- Notebook - FBM's trip to Spain for two weeks, Feb. 8-23, 1952 (Box 4)
- Notebook - FBM's trip to India, 1937 (Box 4)
- Notebook - of addresses and misc. notes. Also death certificate, Apr. 21, 1958, Iowa, driver's license, passport photograph, Rotary Club membership card and calling cards. (Box 4)
- Passports - 1928, 1936, 1946, 1951 (Box 4)
- Notebooks relating to his time at Marshfield High School, Wisconsin
  - Best Herbarium 1901 (Freshman year) (Box 4)
  - Best Kept Notebook - Botany (Box 4)
  - General notebook - Science, Geometry, etc. (Box 4)
  - Notebook - United States (Box 4)
  - Notebook - General History (Box 4)
  - Notebook - His part in a High School debate (Box 4)
- Commencement program, 1904 (Box 4)
- The Philippine Journal of Animal Industry, Sept.-Oct. 1937 (article by FBM) (Box 4)
- Answering Questions on Manchuria, 1936 - South Manchuria Railway Company (Box 4)
- Report of the FAO Mission for Greece, Mar. 1947 (Box 4)
- Bulletin of the Agricultural and Mechanical College of Texas, Summer Session (Box 4)
- The German Universities - A Guide Book for Foreign Students, Deutsche Akademische Auslandsstelle, 1928 (Box 4)
- Story of the Southwest Foundation for Research and Education, 1952 (Box 4)
- SMS Ranches in Texas, Swenson Land & Cattle Co., Inc., n.d. (Box 4)
- "Input and Output Regulationships in Livestock Production, Agric. Econ. Pamph. #38, Jan. 1952 (Box 4)
- The Classification of Carbon Compounds, by Edward Kremers, n.d. (Box 4)
- Dedication Ceremony of Frank B. Morrison Hall and Symposium Papers, Aug. 1962 (Box 4)
- Printed volumes
  - Feeds and Feeding, by W.A. Henry, 2nd Edition, 1900 (Henry's office copy with notes in his handwriting) (Box 5)
  - Feeds and Feeding, by W.A. Henry, 7th Edition, 1906, autographed by Henry (Box 5)
  - Feeds and Feeding, by Henry & Morrison, 19th Edition, 1927, autographed by Morrison (Box 5)
  - Feeds and Feeding, by Morrison, 21st Edition, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Feeds and Feeding, by 22nd Edition, 1956, autographed by Morrison; also new copy of 22nd Edition signed by Morrison shortly before his death (Box 5)
  - Feeds and Feeding Abridged by Henry & Morrison, 6th Edition, 1929 (Box 5)
  - Feeds and Feeding Abridged by Morrison, 7th Edition, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Compendio de Alimentacion del Ganado by F.B. Morrison, adapted from Feeds and Feeding, Mexico, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Alimentos-Alimentacion by F.B. Morrison, Chile, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Paperback book in Russian. Note by Mrs. Morrison, "This is a Russian translation of Feeds and Feeding, made by Imperial Russian Government before the Communists came into Power." (Box 5)
  - Feeds and Feeding Manual by Elmer S. Savage (C.U.) and F.B. Morrison, 1929; 2 copies (Box 5)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Feeds and Feeding, by Elmer S. Savage, 1914 (Box 5)
  - Journal of Animal Science, Nov. 1951. Contains article, "Vitamin and Mineral Supplements for Growing and Fattening Pigs in Drylot," by Noland, Willman and Morrison. (Box 5)
  - Bulletin of the National Research Council, No. 67, "The Minimum Protein Requirements of Cattle," by H.H. Mitchell, 1929. (Box 5)
  - Bulletin of the National Research Council, No. 99, "The Mineral Nutrition of Farm Animals," by H.H. Mitchell and F.J. McClure, 1937. (Box 5)
  - Die wichtigsten Angler Rindviehstamme, 1924. (Box 5)
  - Pamphlet-type book: Städtischer Schlacht- und Viehhof München, 1928 (Box 5)